<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>data viz on Brandon L. Kramer, PhD</title>
    <link>/tags/data-viz/</link>
    <description>Recent content in data viz on Brandon L. Kramer, PhD</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/data-viz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>International Collaboration in Open-Source Software</title>
      <link>/projects/oss/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/oss/</guid>
      <description>Link to the University of Virginia-Biocomplexity Institute&amp;rsquo;s Open-Source Software website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Racialization as Relational Discourse</title>
      <link>/projects/racialization-in-testosterone-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/racialization-in-testosterone-research/</guid>
      <description>This paper is still in the writing phase. Link to GitHub Repository.
Science &amp;amp; technology studies scholars have investigated on how race has been molecularized within scientific studies. And while existing research mainly leans on qualitative strategies such as ethnographies, interviews, and rigorous historical analysis, very little work to date has used social network analysis to study how racial difference is constructed in scientific literature. In this study, I use discourse analysis to first codify racialized claims in a sample of studies that test population differences in the hormone testosterone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Growth of Diversity in Biomedical Research</title>
      <link>/projects/diversity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/diversity/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impacts and Echoes</title>
      <link>/projects/impacts-and-echoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/impacts-and-echoes/</guid>
      <description>Wotecki, C. E., Kramer, B. L., Lancaster, V. &amp;amp; Cohen, S. “Impacts and Echoes: The Lasting Influence of the White House Conference on Food, Nutrition and Health.” Accepted at Annual Review of Nutrition. Links to Interactive Website and GitHub Repository.
The 1969 White House Conference on Food, Nutrition and Health was incredibly influential on the direction of food and nutrition policy in the United States. The conference produced recommendations leading to federal legislation and programs to alleviate hunger and malnutrition, improve consumer’s nutrition knowledge through education and labeling, and monitor the nutritional status of the population.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>