<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ethics on Brandon L. Kramer, Ph.D.</title>
    <link>https://brandonleekramer.github.io/about/tags/ethics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ethics on Brandon L. Kramer, Ph.D.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://brandonleekramer.github.io/about/tags/ethics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Racialization in Testosterone Research</title>
      <link>https://brandonleekramer.github.io/about/projects/race-in-testosterone-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brandonleekramer.github.io/about/projects/race-in-testosterone-research/</guid>
      <description>Kramer, B.L. (2020) “The Molecularization of Race in Testosterone Research.” BioSocieties. GitHub Repo.
While feminist science studies scholars have documented the misleading and dangerous implica-tions of reducing testosterone to a “sex hormone,” few studies have explored how testosterone is used to racialize populations in and beyond scientific research. In this article, I conduct a content analysis of 149 studies that evaluate population differences in testosterone. Despite widespread claims that testosterone varies between racial groups, my analysis of this literature provides scant evidence to support these proclamations, undermining the notion that testosterone contributes to racial differences in biomedical and biosocial outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Growth of Diversity in Biomedical Research</title>
      <link>https://brandonleekramer.github.io/about/projects/diversity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brandonleekramer.github.io/about/projects/diversity/</guid>
      <description>Kramer, B. &amp;amp; Lee, C. “The Rise of Diversity and Population Terminology in Biomedical Research” In Progress. [Project Website] [GitHub Repo]
  While existing research on race and affirmative action have detailed the growth of diversity projects in education and employment that obfuscate the language of race and racism, the field of science &amp;amp; technology studies have documented scientists persistent attempts to molecularize race in biomedical research. In this paper, we employ computational text analysis to examine quantitative trends in the use of diversity terms, OMB/Census terms, and other population labels in a sample of 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gentrification in Fairfax County, VA</title>
      <link>https://brandonleekramer.github.io/about/projects/gentrification/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brandonleekramer.github.io/about/projects/gentrification/</guid>
      <description>Pristavec. P., Kramer, B. L., &amp;amp; Goldstein, J. “Using Publically Available Data to Understand Neighborhood Change and Mitigate Gentrification: A Case Study from Fairfax County, VA.” [GitHub Repo]
  Gentrification refers to the process of areas experiencing an influx of affluent or college-educated residents and businesses, leading to displacement of long-term residents and vulnerable populations. Although research documents gentrification extensively, local governments often lack resources to detect its emergence and mitigate negative community impacts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Molecularization at the Intersections</title>
      <link>https://brandonleekramer.github.io/about/projects/dissertation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brandonleekramer.github.io/about/projects/dissertation/</guid>
      <description>Kramer, B. L. (2019). Molecularization at the Intersections: Testosterone, Prostate Cancer and the Construction of Racial Difference (Doctoral dissertation, Rutgers University-School of Graduate Studies).
Biomedical researchers have long argued that racial differences in testosterone can help explain why African American men have an elevated risk of developing prostate cancer compared to their white counterparts. Using insights from science &amp;amp; technology studies, critical race theory and social network analysis, this dissertation interrogates the linkages between race, testosterone and prostate cancer, showing how testosterone has become racialized in scientific research and the impact that this process has had on the construction of racial disparities in prostate cancer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hair, Hormones, and Haunting</title>
      <link>https://brandonleekramer.github.io/about/projects/pcos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brandonleekramer.github.io/about/projects/pcos/</guid>
      <description>Carlin, L. &amp;amp; Kramer, B.L. (2020). “Hair, Hormones &amp;amp; Ghosts: How Race is Submerged in Polycystic Ovary Syndrome.” Science, Technology &amp;amp; Human Values. (Impact Factor = 3.160).
In this paper, we examine how polycystic ovary syndrome (PCOS) is racialized in biomedical research. Drawing from Star’s seminal concept of triangulation, we analyze how the diagnostic criteria for PCOS combine two different biomarkers: body hair and testosterone. Hair and hormones are both haunted by their use in eugenic research, and as clinical measures, they can carry forward powerful narratives of biological difference.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>