<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Brandon L. Kramer, Ph.D.</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Brandon L. Kramer, Ph.D.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Measuring the Scope and Impact of Open-Source Software</title>
      <link>/projects/oss/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/oss/</guid>
      <description>Current economic indicators and indicators developed by the National Center for Science &amp;amp; Engineering Statistics (NCSES) do not measure the value of goods and services that fall outside of market transactions. Although NCSES does track some types of software development, it is challenging to account for open source software (OSS) outputs because these products are largely being advanced outside of traditional business contexts. Moreover, while current measures of innovation tend to rely on survey data, patent issues, trademarks approvals, intangible asset data, or estimates of total factor productivity growth, these measures are either incomplete or fail to capture innovation that is freely available to the public.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Rise of Diversity in Biomedical Research</title>
      <link>/projects/diversity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/diversity/</guid>
      <description>Kramer, B. &amp;amp; Lee, C. “The Rise of Diversity and Population Terminology in Biomedical Research” In Progress. [Project Website] [GitHub Repo]
 Visit the Project Website Here
 Recent scholarship has highlighted the rise of “diversity projects” across various educational and business contexts, but few studies have detailed what the discourse of diversity does within biomedical research. In this paper, we employ computational text analysis to examine quantitative trends in the use of various forms of diversity and population terminology in a sample of ~2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Racialization in Testosterone Research</title>
      <link>/projects/race-in-testosterone-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/race-in-testosterone-research/</guid>
      <description>Kramer, B.L. (2020) “The Molecularization of Race in Testosterone Research.” BioSocieties. GitHub Repo.
While feminist science studies scholars have documented the misleading and dangerous implica-tions of reducing testosterone to a “sex hormone,” few studies have explored how testosterone is used to racialize populations in and beyond scientific research. In this article, I conduct a content analysis of 149 studies that evaluate population differences in testosterone. Despite widespread claims that testosterone varies between racial groups, my analysis of this literature provides scant evidence to support these proclamations, undermining the notion that testosterone contributes to racial differences in biomedical and biosocial outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hair, Hormones, and Haunting</title>
      <link>/projects/pcos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/pcos/</guid>
      <description>Carlin, L. &amp;amp; Kramer, B.L. (2020). “Hair, Hormones &amp;amp; Ghosts: How Race is Submerged in Polycystic Ovary Syndrome.” Science, Technology &amp;amp; Human Values. (Impact Factor = 3.160).
In this paper, we examine how polycystic ovary syndrome (PCOS) is racialized in biomedical research. Drawing from Star’s seminal concept of triangulation, we analyze how the diagnostic criteria for PCOS combine two different biomarkers: body hair and testosterone. Hair and hormones are both haunted by their use in eugenic research, and as clinical measures, they can carry forward powerful narratives of biological difference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Predictive Analytics to Study Gentrification</title>
      <link>/projects/gentrification/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/gentrification/</guid>
      <description>Pristavec. P., Kramer, B. L., &amp;amp; Goldstein, J. “Using Publically Available Data to Understand Neighborhood Change and Mitigate Gentrification: A Case Study from Fairfax County, VA.” [GitHub Repo]
 
 Gentrification refers to the process of areas experiencing an influx of affluent or college-educated residents and businesses, leading to displacement of long-term residents and vulnerable populations. Although research documents gentrification extensively, local governments often lack resources to detect its emergence and mitigate negative community impacts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measuring Stress Reactivity to Masculinity Threats</title>
      <link>/projects/masculinity-and-stress/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/masculinity-and-stress/</guid>
      <description>Kramer, B.L., Himmelstein, M.S., &amp;amp; Springer, K.W. (2017). Getting to the heart of masculinity stressors: Masculinity threats induce pronounced vagal withdrawal during a speaking task. Annals of Behavioral Medicine, 51(6), 846-855. (Impact Factor = 3.118).
In this study, we use an experimental framework to fill three existing gaps in the masculinities and health literatures. First, we examine the impact of masculinity threats on cortisol reactivity to understand how hegemonic masculinity gets “under the skin” to affect men’s health.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impacts and Echoes (The History of Nutrition Science in the US)</title>
      <link>/projects/impacts-and-echoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/impacts-and-echoes/</guid>
      <description>Wotecki, C. E., Kramer, B. L., Lancaster, V. &amp;amp; Cohen, S. (2020). “Impacts and Echoes: The Lasting Influence of the White House Conference on Food, Nutrition and Health.” Annual Review of Nutrition. [Impact Factor = 10.897] [GitHub Repo] [Project Abstract]
This is text network of 1969 White House Conference Report where important terms used in the text are represented as bubbles (or nodes) with connections (or ties) corresponding to how often those terms are used together in the report.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evidence Exchange in Federal Policymaking</title>
      <link>/projects/evidence-exchange/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/evidence-exchange/</guid>
      <description>Kramer, B., Weber, M. &amp;amp; Yanovitsky, I. Networks of Evidence Use in the Context of Federal Childhood Obesity Policymaking. In Progress. [GitHub Repo] [EPIK website]
Despite considerable interest in strategies for promoting evidence-informed policymaking, research that tracks and analyzes use of research evidence in public policymaking is scarce. We use social network analysis to trace the flow of research evidence in the context of childhood obesity legislation from 2000-2014. Network analysis is used to examine how political homophily, or policymakers’ shared group affiliations, and various structural characteristics of the policy network influence evidence exchange over this period.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Molecularization at the Intersections (Dissertation)</title>
      <link>/projects/dissertation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/dissertation/</guid>
      <description>Kramer, B. L. (2019). Molecularization at the Intersections: Testosterone, Prostate Cancer and the Construction of Racial Difference (Doctoral dissertation, Rutgers University-School of Graduate Studies).
Biomedical researchers have long argued that racial differences in testosterone can help explain why African American men have an elevated risk of developing prostate cancer compared to their white counterparts. Using insights from science &amp;amp; technology studies, critical race theory and social network analysis, this dissertation interrogates the linkages between race, testosterone and prostate cancer, showing how testosterone has become racialized in scientific research and the impact that this process has had on the construction of racial disparities in prostate cancer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/to_add/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/to_add/publications/</guid>
      <description>Publications Kramer, B.L. (2020). &amp;ldquo;The Molecularization of Race in Testosterone Research.&amp;rdquo; BioSocieties. [Impact Factor = 3.083] [GitHub Repo] [Project Abstract]
Wotecki, C. E., Kramer, B. L., Lancaster, V. &amp;amp; Cohen, S. (2020). “Impacts and Echoes: The Lasting Influence of the White House Conference on Food, Nutrition and Health.” Annual Review of Nutrition. [Impact Factor = 10.897] [GitHub Repo] [Project Abstract]
Carlin, L. &amp;amp; Kramer, B.L. (2020). “Hair, Hormones &amp;amp; Ghosts: How Race is Submerged in Polycystic Ovary Syndrome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>/* this chunnk of code centers all of the headings */ h1, h2, h3, h4, h5 { text-align: center; }    Brandon Kramer, Ph.D. Computational Social Scientist  Email - GitHub   Hi, I am Brandon Kramer and I’m currently a Postdoctoral Research Associate in the Social and Decision Analytics Division at the University of Virginia’s Biocomplexity Institute. Generally, I research innovation and inequality at the intersection of science, technology, and health.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/</guid>
      <description>/* this chunnk of code centers all of the headings */ h1, h2, h3, h4, h5 { text-align: center; }  Publications Kramer, B.L. (2020). “The Molecularization of Race in Testosterone Research.” BioSocieties. [Impact Factor = 3.083] [GitHub Repo] [Project Abstract]
Wotecki, C. E., Kramer, B. L., Lancaster, V. &amp;amp; Cohen, S. (2020). “Impacts and Echoes: The Lasting Influence of the White House Conference on Food, Nutrition and Health.” Annual Review of Nutrition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/</guid>
      <description>In their dissertation project (completed in Spring 2019 at Rutgers University), Brandon studied how testosterone has been used to racialize populations in biomedical research and the effect that this process has had on the construction of racial health disparities. By integrating various qualitative strategies with network analysis, Brandon traced how testosterone researchers advance misleading and dangerous claims about racial differences in health and behavior, ultimately arguing that these discourses contribute to racially-specific healthcare practices that exacerbate prostate cancer disparities between white and black men.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resources/</guid>
      <description>/* this chunnk of code centers all of the headings */ h1, h2, h3, h4, h5 { text-align: center; }  Online Tutorials  Making Websites in Hugo/Blogdown
Quick Version
Mindware Cardiovascular Data Cleaning Tutorial
Part 1 - Part 2 - Part 3 - Part 4 - Part 5 - Part 6 - Part 7
Using Web of Science Data for Social Network Analysis in Gephi
 
 Course Syllabus  Sociology of Medicine and Healthcare (Rutgers - Fall 2017)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/teaching/</guid>
      <description>/* this chunnk of code centers all of the headings */ h1, h2, h3, h4, h5 { text-align: center; }  Mentoring &amp;amp; Teaching Experience 
Rutgers University - Department of Sociology Over the past five years, I have taught and mentored in a variety of contexts, but my experience is a bit unconventional from most social scientists. During my time at Rutgers University, I was an Instructor for the Sociology of Medicine and Health Care for two semesters (Spring-Fall 2017) as well as a teaching assistant for Contemporary Sociological Theory (Spring 2016) and Introduction to Sociological Research Methods (Fall 2016).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>/to_add/trainings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/to_add/trainings/</guid>
      <description> DSPG https://datascienceforthepublicgood.org/events/symposium2020 https://dspg-young-scholars-program.github.io/dspg20oss/ https://dspg-young-scholars-program.github.io/dspg20fairfax/ https://dspg-young-scholars-program.github.io/dspg2020amsoldier/ https://teja.shinyapps.io/patrickdash/
 Biosocial training Embed links for training videos
 Networks Basic network training video Getting started in Gephi Making visuals in Gephi
 Websites Download templates Editing CSS and html Deploying to GitHub pages Deploying to Netlify
 Links to courses  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>