<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>health disparities on Brandon L. Kramer, PhD</title>
    <link>/tags/health-disparities/</link>
    <description>Recent content in health disparities on Brandon L. Kramer, PhD</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/health-disparities/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hair, Hormones, and Haunting</title>
      <link>/projects/pcos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/pcos/</guid>
      <description>Carlin, L. &amp;amp; Kramer, B.L. (2020). “Hair, Hormones &amp;amp; Ghosts: How Race is Submerged in Polycystic Ovary Syndrome.” Science, Technology &amp;amp; Human Values. (Impact Factor = 3.160).
In this paper, we examine how polycystic ovary syndrome (PCOS) is racialized in biomedical research. Drawing from Star’s seminal concept of triangulation, we analyze how the diagnostic criteria for PCOS combine two different biomarkers: body hair and testosterone. Hair and hormones are both haunted by their use in eugenic research, and as clinical measures, they can carry forward powerful narratives of biological difference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impacts and Echoes</title>
      <link>/projects/impacts-and-echoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/impacts-and-echoes/</guid>
      <description>Wotecki, C. E., Kramer, B. L., Lancaster, V. &amp;amp; Cohen, S. “Impacts and Echoes: The Lasting Influence of the White House Conference on Food, Nutrition and Health.” Revise &amp;amp; Resubmit at Annual Review of Nutrition. Links to Interactive Website and GitHub Repository.
The 1969 White House Conference on Food, Nutrition and Health was incredibly influential on the direction of food and nutrition policy in the United States. The conference produced recommendations leading to federal legislation and programs to alleviate hunger and malnutrition, improve consumer’s nutrition knowledge through education and labeling, and monitor the nutritional status of the population.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stress in Strong Convictions</title>
      <link>/projects/stress-in-strong-convictions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/stress-in-strong-convictions/</guid>
      <description>Himmelstein, M. S., Kramer, B. L., &amp;amp; Springer, K. W. (2019). Stress in strong convictions: Precarious manhood beliefs moderate cortisol reactivity to masculinity threats. Psychology of Men &amp;amp; Masculinities., 20(4), 491–502. (Impact Factor = 1.813)
In this study, we use an experimental framework to fill three existing gaps in the masculinities and health literatures. First, we examine the impact of masculinity threats on cortisol reactivity to understand how hegemonic masculinity gets “under the skin” to affect men’s health.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Molecularization at the Intersections</title>
      <link>/projects/dissertation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/dissertation/</guid>
      <description>Kramer, B. L. (2019). Molecularization at the Intersections: Testosterone, Prostate Cancer and the Construction of Racial Difference (Doctoral dissertation, Rutgers University-School of Graduate Studies).
Biomedical researchers have long argued that racial differences in testosterone can help explain why African American men have an elevated risk of developing prostate cancer compared to their white counterparts. Using insights from science &amp;amp; technology studies, critical race theory and social network analysis, this dissertation interrogates the linkages between race, testosterone and prostate cancer, showing how testosterone has become racialized in scientific research and the impact that this process has had on the construction of racial disparities in prostate cancer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting to the Heart of Masculinity Stressors</title>
      <link>/projects/getting-to-the-heart/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/getting-to-the-heart/</guid>
      <description>Kramer, B.L., Himmelstein, M.S., &amp;amp; Springer, K.W. (2017). Getting to the heart of masculinity stressors: Masculinity threats induce pronounced vagal withdrawal during a speaking task. Annals of Behavioral Medicine, 51(6), 846-855. (Impact Factor = 3.118).
In this study, we use an experimental framework to fill three existing gaps in the masculinities and health literatures. First, we examine the impact of masculinity threats on cortisol reactivity to understand how hegemonic masculinity gets “under the skin” to affect men’s health.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>