<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>viz on Brandon L. Kramer, Ph.D.</title>
    <link>https://brandonleekramer.github.io/about/tags/viz/</link>
    <description>Recent content in viz on Brandon L. Kramer, Ph.D.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://brandonleekramer.github.io/about/tags/viz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Growth of Diversity in Biomedical Research</title>
      <link>https://brandonleekramer.github.io/about/projects/diversity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brandonleekramer.github.io/about/projects/diversity/</guid>
      <description>Kramer, B. &amp;amp; Lee, C. “The Rise of Diversity and Population Terminology in Biomedical Research” In Progress. [Project Website] [GitHub Repo]
  While existing research on race and affirmative action have detailed the growth of diversity projects in education and employment that obfuscate the language of race and racism, the field of science &amp;amp; technology studies have documented scientists persistent attempts to molecularize race in biomedical research. In this paper, we employ computational text analysis to examine quantitative trends in the use of diversity terms, OMB/Census terms, and other population labels in a sample of 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measuring the Scope and Impact of Open-Source Software</title>
      <link>https://brandonleekramer.github.io/about/projects/oss/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brandonleekramer.github.io/about/projects/oss/</guid>
      <description>Current economic indicators and indicators developed by the National Center for Science &amp;amp; Engineering Statistics (NCSES) do not measure the value of goods and services that fall outside of market transactions. Although NCSES does track some types of software development, it is challenging to account for open source software (OSS) outputs because these products are largely being advanced outside of traditional business contexts. Moreover, while current measures of innovation tend to rely on survey data, patent issues, trademarks approvals, intangible asset data, or estimates of total factor productivity growth, these measures are either incomplete or fail to capture innovation that is freely available to the public.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gentrification in Fairfax County, VA</title>
      <link>https://brandonleekramer.github.io/about/projects/gentrification/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brandonleekramer.github.io/about/projects/gentrification/</guid>
      <description>Pristavec. P., Kramer, B. L., &amp;amp; Goldstein, J. “Using Publically Available Data to Understand Neighborhood Change and Mitigate Gentrification: A Case Study from Fairfax County, VA.” [GitHub Repo]
  Gentrification refers to the process of areas experiencing an influx of affluent or college-educated residents and businesses, leading to displacement of long-term residents and vulnerable populations. Although research documents gentrification extensively, local governments often lack resources to detect its emergence and mitigate negative community impacts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impacts and Echoes</title>
      <link>https://brandonleekramer.github.io/about/projects/impacts-and-echoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brandonleekramer.github.io/about/projects/impacts-and-echoes/</guid>
      <description>Wotecki, C. E., Kramer, B. L., Lancaster, V. &amp;amp; Cohen, S. (2020). “Impacts and Echoes: The Lasting Influence of the White House Conference on Food, Nutrition and Health.” Annual Review of Nutrition. [Impact Factor = 10.897] [GitHub Repo] [Project Abstract]
This is text network of 1969 White House Conference Report where important terms used in the text are represented as bubbles (or nodes) with connections (or ties) corresponding to how often those terms are used together in the report.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>