<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>nlp on Brandon L. Kramer, Ph.D. </title>
    <link>/tags/nlp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in nlp on Brandon L. Kramer, Ph.D. </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/nlp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Measuring the Scope and Impact of Open-Source Software</title>
      <link>/projects/oss/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/oss/</guid>
      <description>Current economic indicators and indicators developed by the National Center for Science &amp;amp; Engineering Statistics (NCSES) do not measure the value of goods and services that fall outside of market transactions. Although NCSES does track some types of software development, it is challenging to account for open source software (OSS) outputs because these products are largely being advanced outside of traditional business contexts. Moreover, while current measures of innovation tend to rely on survey data, patent issues, trademarks approvals, intangible asset data, or estimates of total factor productivity growth, these measures are either incomplete or fail to capture innovation that is freely available to the public.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Growth of Diversity in Biomedical Research</title>
      <link>/projects/diversity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/diversity/</guid>
      <description>Kramer, B. &amp;amp; Lee, C. “The Growth of Diversity in Biomedical Research” In Progress. [Project Website] [GitHub Repo]
While existing research on race and affirmative action have documented the growth of diversity projects in education and employment, the field of science &amp;amp; technology studies have documented the persistence of scientists to molecularize race in biomedical research. In our paper, we employ computational text analysis to examine quantitative patterns in the use of diversity and population-specific terminology in biomedical research over the course of the past three decades.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impacts and Echoes</title>
      <link>/projects/impacts-and-echoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/impacts-and-echoes/</guid>
      <description>Wotecki, C. E., Kramer, B. L., Lancaster, V. &amp;amp; Cohen, S. (2020). “Impacts and Echoes: The Lasting Influence of the White House Conference on Food, Nutrition and Health.” Annual Review of Nutrition. [Impact Factor = 10.897] [GitHub Repo] [Project Abstract]
This is text network of 1969 White House Conference Report where important terms used in the text are represented as bubbles (or nodes) with connections (or ties) corresponding to how often those terms are used together in the report.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>